Finding Aid for the Japanese American Research Project Collection about Japanese in the U.S. (Yuji Ichioka papers) LSC.2010.00
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Oral History Tapes
  - Tapes M155-M168. (Box 845)
    Interviewees include: Matsusaburo Nagata, Joseph Shigeo Aoki, Frank Ogawa, Heizo Oshima, Hikoichi Tajima, Chiura Obata, Henry Moriya Takahashi, Junichi Kami, Toichi Domoto, Sam Sakai, Reverend Gordon Chapman, Motoji Kitano, and Kamezuchi Sakamoto.
  - Tapes M169-M182. (Box 846)
    Interviewees include: Shinobu Matsuura, Suzie Tanaka Kreider, Thomas Shinichiro Oka, Mine Shigematsu, Tomiyo Uyeyama, Chisato Kawamoto, Harry N. Sato, Eisaburo Abe, Toshio Inouye, Shotaro Otsubo, Eiichi Yamamoto, Soichi Nakatani, Ichiji Sugiyama, Withney M. Young, Jr., and Colonel Sidney Forrester Mashbir.
  - Tapes M183-M196. (Box 847)
    Interviewees include: Colonel Sidney Forrester Mashbir, Colonel Verne Austin, Saburo Kido, Rindge Shima, Mike M. Masaoka, Phoebe Asano, Mrs. H. M. Otsuki, Reverend Hiram K. Kano, Shinkichi Tokunaga, Otsuji Kageyama, Inokichi Fukuda, Harry Yuhei Ujifusa, Zadankai at Buddhist Church, Sojiro Yoritomo, Fred Nobuichi Kawamura, Reverend Yoshitaka Tamai, Reverend Ryotetsu Kazumata, Reverend Jonathon Fujita, Dr. Frank Eizo Hayano, Heijiro Nakano, Reverend Ryotetsu Kazumata, Seishiro Nakamura, Buddhist Church, and Simpson Methodist Church.
  - Tapes M197-M210., circa 1967 (Box 848)
    Interviewees include: Minoru Yasui, Reverend Theodore Kamasuke Chinen, Thomas S. Higa, Toshiyuki Hirabayashi, Barton H. Nagata, Y. Baron Goto, Adam A. Smyser, Governor John A. Burns, Koji Ariyoshi, Justice Masaji Marumoto, Masayuki Tokioka, Katsuro Miho, and George J. Fukunaga.
  - Tapes M211-M224. (Box 849)
    Interviewees include: Yutaka Doi, Noboru Miyake, Harvey S. Kawakami, Hiro Higuchi, Mark Y. Murakami, Yoneto Yamaguchi, Mayor Shunichi Kimura, Nelson K. Doi, Tsutomu Taketa, C.S.E.S Class (Warren Furutani, Mike Yamaki), Donald Tokunaga, Thomas S. Yagi, Daniel T. Shigeta, Benjamin M. Tashiro, Yasui-Yoshizu families, group interview (Mrs. Kiyo Kasai, Mrs. Toshiko Abe, Mrs. Y. Murakami, Mr. C. Kanamoto, Mr. S. Wakamatsu, Mrs. Yori Endo, Mrs. H. Y. Kawamura, Mrs. S. Inashima, Mrs. S. Y. Okota, Mrs. M. Yamada), Takemaru Kirakara, Henry Fujii, Mrs. Roy Abe, Mrs. S. Kawa, John Arima, and Takashi Koyama.
  - Tapes M225-M238., circa 1965-1966 (Box 850)
    Interviewees include: Takemaru Kirakara, Henry Fujii, Mrs. Roy Abe, Mrs. S. Kawa, John Arima, Takashi Koyama, Sashichi S. Koyama, F. A. Huntley, Henry Hajimu, Henry Hajimu Fiyii, Mrs. Roy Abe, Mrs. S. Kawai, Takemaru Hirahara, Richard Suenaga, Matsuko Orita, Bunji Takano, Tomejiro Shigetoni, Jingoro Ozaki, Kiyoshi Joichi, Kintaro Yogi, Jingoro Ozaki, Kiyoshi Joichi, Kintaro Yogi, group conversation (Kenji Nakane, Ralph Kanzaki, Yutaka Kanemoto, Yukio Hashiguchi, Paul Shimokuto), Dr. Newton K. Wesley, Noriaki Okada, and Mr. and Mrs. Chozo Kumagai.
  - Tapes M239-M252., circa 1966 (Box 851)
    Interviewees include: Earl M. Harano, Toshiro Yamagida, Kaz Tokichi, Mike Watanabe, Jim Mizeno, Tom Arikawa, Harry G. Watanabe, Gladys S. Hirabayashi, Cecil J. Ishii, Kiyoko Watanabe, Ritta Moie, Mrs. Moto Fukui, Ida Fukui, Tom Oki, Leo Yamamoto, Mr. and Mrs. Mas Baka, Eunice Oshima, Ida Fukui, Mr. and Mrs. Fred Aoyama, Mr. and Mrs. Paul Nozu, Wilson Makabe, Mr. and Mrs. Sonao Imagire, Chika Tsujimichi, Shizu Matsumoto, Kametaro Ishii, Janet (Shigeko) Kikukshima, and Mr. and Mrs. Yoshitaro Baba.
  - Tapes M253-M266. (Box 852)
    Interviewees include: Hatsutaro Chikami, Kengo Benjamin Takenaka, Edward J. Ennis, Moonray Kojima, Yae Murata, Mr. Taichi Yatsu, Mrs. Satsuyo Ohmura, Masami Asai, Ray Tsuyoshi Yasui, Henry T. Kato, George Nakamura, Ray Sato, Kozo Miyako, Umata Matsushima, George Tanezo Niiyama, Roy Y. Yokota, Newton Noboru Takashima, Henry Kato, Mr. and Mrs. Katsuharu Nakashima, and Tamaichi Yamada. Also includes the biography of Kawayama Senjo.
  - Tapes M267-M280., circa 1966-1967 (Box 853)
    Interviewees include: Tamaichi Yamada, James Keijiro Kida, Henry Hitoshi Nakamura, Seishichi Matsumoto, Mrs. Masuko Kawasoe, Mrs. Hatsui Ureii, Ms. Yuki Sato, Frank Ogami, Harry Kuramoto, Harry H. Morikamu, Kango Wada, Kiuda Ouchida, Jack T. Ouchida, Mrs. Haru Tsuji, Elmer Y. Nishimoto, Mitsuo Nakata, D.D., Harry Kuramoto, Bob Uriu, John Arima, George Sugai, Taka Akita, Ben Tsykamaki, Dr. George Iwasa, George Iseri, Teruo Tsuboi, Naoko Tanida, John Adrian Rademaker, Dr. Mitsuo Nakata, Dr. Matthew M. Masuoka, Henry D. Kato, Ike Iwasaki, and Tamaichi Yamada.
  - Tapes M281-M294. (Box 854)
    Interviewees include: Sadaji Shiogi, Misao Yada, Katsuharu Nakashima, Yasukichi Iwasaki, Satsuyo Kawano, John Nitta, William Marutani, Tom Tamaki, Mr. and Mrs. Yonakichi Kagawa, Mrs. Watanabe (George Waki's mother-in-law), Mrs. Kiyoko Arai, Mrs. Wakei Sando, and Mr. Hachiro Sawamura.
  - Tapes M295-M308., circa 1966 (Box 855)
    Interviewees include: Mr. Paul S. Katsuro, Mannosuke Shiraishi, Koe Hanaye, Eyiro Kawamura, Tadashi Nakata, Matajiro Watada, Katshei Sakaguchi, Togo Nakano, Lee Murata, Reverend Y. Tamai, Chieko H. Ogawa, Thomas Tomichei Ogawa, Harry Hiyoza Kumagai, Kame Toyota, Rupert Hachiya, Josie Hachiya, Elna Mya, Yukiko Kimura, Alice Kanai, Shiago Tokunaga, Sue Kaneko, Chiyomaten Shiozawa, Yukiko Kimura, Elna Miya (Miyagishima) Harry M. Eda, Roy R. Takada, Charles S. Kawakami, Yosh Amano, Frank Tamagawa, Mary Kawakami, Shozu Niwa, Kuniko Terasawa, Terry "Terumasa" Adachi, Alice Kasai, Mitsuko Sasaki, and Naoki and Sakae Kobayashi.
  - Tapes M309-M322., circa 1966-1967 (Box 856)
    Interviewees include: Mrs. Kuniko Terasawa, Terry "Terumasa" Adachi, Alice Kasai, Mitsuko Sasaki, Naoki and Sakae Kobayashi, Utah Buddhist Church, Jiro Mochizuki, Daisuke Miyatake, Matajuro Ushio, Bunzo Fujii, Torn Shimizu, Gin Namba, Mataju Ushio, Charles J. Umemura, Shigao Tokunaga, Esther Hirasawa, Hiro Yasukochi, Jiro Mochizuki, Mr. and Mrs. Hinokichi Kawaguchi, Kamasaku Miyagishima, Ogden Japanese Union Church, Intermountain District Council, Tosh Kano, Japanese Church of Christ, Takeshi Kubota, Kazumi Mizote, Shigeru Osawa, Tadashi Yamaguchi, Dick Kanaya, and Reverend Emery E. Andrews.
  - Tapes M323-M336. (Box 857)
    Interviewees include: Genji Mihara, Harry Sotaro Kawabe, Mrs. Nobuko Suzuki, Minoru Masuda, Shigeru Asawa, Ralph Y. Kono, Frank Hattori, George Susumu Ota, Thomas T. Sakahara, Arthur Ichiro Somekawa, Shuichi Fukui, Seiichi Tamaki, Chuji Ray Takahashi, Naonobu Mizukami, Shikataro Nakagawara, and Toraichi Seto.
  - Tapes M337-M350., circa 1965 (Box 858)
    Interviewees include: Gohachi Yoshida, Yasukichi Hamanishi, Goroku Kubo, Tsugio Yaguchi, Shintaro Takagi, Sam Kubata, Buheiji Hattori, Yashino Hattori, Sam Kubata, Hatsuzoro Toda, Yoshito Fujii, and Masanori Sato.
  - Tapes M351-M364. (Box 859)
    Interviewees include: Tom Shoji Yamamoto, Kumaichi Horike, Lillian Katsuyo Takeshita, Miyo Nishio, Dillon S. Myer, Francis Biddle, Clarke H. Kawakami, Roger Baldwin, Arthur McCollum, Spark M. Matsunaga, and "To Age 10 Years."
  - Tapes M265-M378., circa 1966 (Box 860)
    Interviewees include: Johnny Kiyoshi Saiki, B. Tomizo Miyamoto, Itsuki Hashimoto, Tatsuhei Tsuda, Tommy Tadayoshi Shito, James M. Kuga, Mrs. Karuko Kobayashi, Min Yasui, Robert A. Wilson, Joe Grant Masaoka, Sojiro Yoritomo, Jusafuro Sakata, Mrs. Toki Sakata, Gontaro Kubota, Mrs. Kiyo Kubota, Mrs. Hana Hayachi, Mrs. Tsuta Kushibashi, Togo Tanaka, Gordon Hirabayashi, Professor Robert A. Wilson, 14th Biennial I.D.C. Convention, Civil Rights Workshop, and Gordon K. Hirabayashi.
  - Tapes M379-392., circa 1966-1968 (Box 861)
    Interviewees include: Regional Conference of the Association for Asian Studies, JACL Convention Banquet, Chohei Kondo, Sam Kido Testimonial, Robert A. Wilson classes, Representative Spark Matsunaga, Frank F. Chuman, Alan Kumanoto, Mori Nishida, Glenn Matsumoto, George Takei, and Joe Grant Masaoka.
  - Tapes M393-M396. (Box 862)
    Interviewees include: Robert A. Wilson class, Dr. Gene Levine - seminars 1-2, and Professor Inamoto talk.
  - Transcripts of tapes, 0.5 linear ft.
    The original tapes corresponding to these transcripts can be found in boxes 380-383.
    - #24 - Iwata, Masakasi. (Box 519)
    - #33 - Koide, Joe. (Box 519)
    - #53 - Miyamoto, David. (Box 519)
    - #54 - Miyatake, Toyo. (Box 519)
    - #59 - Okazaki, Robert I. (Box 519)
    - #68 - Oriental Actors. (Box 519)
- Sumitomo Bank of California Photographs, 1976; 1.0 linear ft.
  The Sumitomo Bank of California Photographs are enlarged and mounted black and white reproductions of photographs depicting the accomplishments and daily life of Japanese Americans from 1887 to 1976. The majority of the photographs document Japanese living on the west coast, particularly in California. These photograph reproductions were originally part of "The Japanese American Contribution" exhibit hosted by the Sumitomo Bank of California in 1976.
  For additional source see online finding aid: Sumitomo Bank of California photographs (Collection 2010)
- Miscellaneous Items, various dates; 13.5 linear ft.
  - Nakamura Collection: Boy's Day dolls. (Box 752, Box 747-749; 750-751)
  - Scrolls, Hagoita, and other items. (Box 753-754)
  - Photographs and negatives of Japan and China, early Meiji. (Box 755)
    [Negatives UNAVAILABLE - stored in nitrate vault]
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings and scrapbooks. (Box 756-760)
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings., (2 scrapbooks) (Box 761)
  - Matted black and white photographic print of the 1907 reception in Tacoma, Washington, for Ishii Kikujiro, Head of the Commerce Bureau in Japan. (Box 744)
  - Yearbooks and diaries., 1910s and n.d.; (8 items including 4 reels of microfilm) (Box 868, Box 867)
    Diaries in Box 868 are by Yasukuchi Iwasaki. Also a note that diaries are by an Oregon immigrant farmer (name not given in note). Also, Chinese Consulate microfilm and unidentified (in English) Japanese microfilm.
    Two diaries in Box 867 are from 1913 and 1916. The authors are unknown.
    Added October 1997.
    Added 1975-.
  - Silk textiles - instruction banner with carbon based ink and hand painted handkerchief (Roll 875)
- Nissei and Sansei Survey, undated; 23.0 linear ft.
  - Original returns. (Box 568-614)
- University of Hawaii at Manoa [Oral History Interviews], 1977; 1.5 linear ft.
  - Waialua and Haleiwa: the people tell their story [Transcripts of oral history interviews]., 1977 (Box 616-618)
    [Indexes at Special Collections Reference Desk]
    - Volume I: Caucasians, Chinese, and Hawaiians. (Box 616)
    - Volume II: Koreans and Puerto Ricans. (Box 616)
    - Volumes III & IV: Filipinos (A-Z). (Box 616)
    - Volumes V - VII: Japanese (A-Z). (Box 617)
    - Volumes VIII & IX: Portuguese (A-Z). (Box 618)
- Siberius Y. Saito Drawings, undated; 1.0 linear ft.
  - Drawings. (Box 620)